Now, in this lecture, we're going to do a console walkthrough of the MSN bedrock
service so that you can understand at a high level what are all the capabilities that are
available as part of the service. Now, let's head over to the AWS console. Now,
I'm on the AWS console. Now, let me just search for Amazon bedrock.
And you can see the Amazon bedrock service here. So, let me just click on this.
So, now I'm on the Amazon bedrock service. So, you can see on the left hand side,
all the capabilities that are offered as part of this service. So, we're going to deep dive
into each of these aspects as we go along in the course. But for now, I'm just going to give
a high level overview so that you get a mental model of all the capabilities that are available.
So, if you don't understand some parts of it, that's okay, where anyway, we're going to deep dive
into all of them in detail in the later sections. So, first we have the overview. So, here you can see
model catalog and then you can see test, chat. So, it's basically a replica of what we have here.
Next, we have the model catalog. So, it will provide you a list of all the models that are
available from different model providers as for this bedrock service. So, you can see all the
models that are here and if I just continue to scroll, you will see all the different models.
So, the key thing you want to keep in mind is this model collection. So, some of the models
are available as serverless and some are available as part of the bedrock marketplace. So, if I
just click on the serverless, you can see cloud and then you will be able to see some models from
meta, etc. So, all these models that are available as part of the serverless service, AWS will
take care of the hosting of the model, scaling, monitoring, etc. And you just pay based on the number
of EPA requests. So, there is no commitment. Now, it's just good to the models that are available
as part of the bedrock marketplace and here is some of the models that are available.
So, if we just click on this first one. So, with this writer met 70 b 32 k and what is its focus
category, text duration, its available delivery method Amazon bedrock and Amazon SageMaker. So,
it will provide you all the details, but the key thing to note here is when you are selecting a model
from the marketplace deployment, you will be charged by the model provider, but you will also be
charged a fixed cost. So, you can see here you have to provision this instance type which is going
to charge you 57.1 dollars per hour. So, there is going to be infrastructure cost and then there is
going to charge from the model provider which is this one in this case. So, that's something you should
remember. So, next we have the APA keys. So, Amazon bedrock service allows you to generate short-term
and long-term APA keys through which you can make APA request to the bedrock service
programmatically. So, you can generate the short-term key which is valid for 12 hours and then
you can also generate the long-term key. So, for long-term keys you can see here we strongly recommend
using long-term keys only for exploratory purposes to avoid security risk and production.
So, what it is strongly recommends is that if you are using in the production then you just go ahead
and use the identity and access management with STS token rather than these short-term or long-term
keys. But if you are just using as an exploratory purpose or let's say a building an agent
application and using open source a framework which requires APA keys and then in that scenario you
should use short-term and long-term keys. And how do you generate the keys? So, you can see here
generate short-term keys. So, if you just click on this it will generate the APA key for me.
Next we have the test. So, this is enabled. So, let's say you want to build a genetic application.
But before you start building programmatically the application you may want to just test out your
foundation models or if you're using an image model you can just test this out from the console
and see if it is giving you the right response or if you want to compare different models. So,
that's what this test capability can be used for. So, if you just click on this chat text. So,
if you just click on select model it will show you all the model providers. So, maybe I'll
select Amazon then I can select the right model that I want. So, I'll click on our pro apply.
Then I can just paste some sample prompt and see if I get the requisite response. So, maybe I'll
just say so maybe I'll just say what is Amazon bedrock and if I just do a run so it's going to give
me a response. And then in this way I can just change the model and maybe have some other models
and compare different models. So, now if I just go back to the bedrock service. Similarly,
let's say you work in advertising and you need models that can generate images or videos for you.
You can just test that out from here. Select the model here. So, right now it has modeled only
from Amazon and these are the four models. So, if I just click on no one canvas apply then I can
just put a prompt here and let you just put a simple prompt image of a dog. If I just run
and now it has generated multiple images and then you can make some configuration changes here
and you might see different results. So, in this way you can use different models here
and compare before you actually start building the application.
Next we have this watermark detection. So, what watermark detection does? It detects whether the
image was generated by Titan image generator or Nova canvas model on bedrock. So, what you can do is
let's say you want to determine if this is an AI generated image or this is an original image you
can just you can just choose image maybe just upload the image and then just click on analyze.
So, it can tell you whether the image and you can see here the results it says the watermark
not detected. So, bedrock did not detect a watermark generated by bedrock model on this image.
So, next you have the tokenizer. You can see here when you run inferences with foundation models you
are charged on the number of tokens in your input and output. So, with the tokenizer you can
estimate the number of tokens in your input and refine as necessary to account for your cost
as well as token quotas. So, what I can do is I can select the model. So, let's say I choose
anthropic and cloud and just to apply and then here I will put the input text that will typically
be sent by my end user. Let's just say insert sample token and then I can just click on
count token and you can see 17 tokens. So, it will help you understand how many tokens would be
consumed and then you can go to the bedrock pricing table and determine what is the approximate cost
and we are going to get in the costing a little later, but for now tokenizer helps you identify
the number of tokens that will be consumed for your input and output. Now, before we continue,
I just want to reiterate that I am just giving you a hell of an overview of all the capabilities
within the Amazon bedrock service and if you have not understood some of those concepts it is
okay. We are going to deep dive into all of these concepts in the later lectures in this course.
So, next we have infer and we have cross region inference. So, cross region inference uses
inference profile to increase throughput and improve resilience by routing your requests across
multiple AWS regions during peak utilization burst. So, the scenario for using cross region
inferences, let's say you built a highly critical generative AI application. So, there could be
some very rare circumstances where your application may experience throttling. So, there is not enough
capacity to service your request by the Amazon bedrock service in that particular region.
So, in those scenarios, you can choose cross region inference and what bedrock service will do is
if it does not have enough capacity, it is going to reroute that request to a different region.
But you need to be careful on which scenarios you can use cross region inference so that it does
not conflict with some of the geographic regulations like GDPR where you cannot send the data
outside the European Union. Next we have the batch inference. So, batch inference,
run model inference isynchronously in batches to efficiently process many requests at once.
Now, let's say for an insurance company you built a generative AI application which processes
lot of claim letters and you don't need to process those letters immediately. So, you can create a
overnight batch of and you can run all of those claim letters as part of the batch job.
So, what is the benefit? Batch inference speeds up inferences on large datasets and in some scenarios
it can cost 50% less than on demand. And remember that on demand means that your request
is processed real time and you pay based on the number for request you make.
Okay, next we have the provision throughput. Again, project throughput allows you to have
dedicated capacity to deploy your models. So, what it means is again, let's say you have a critical
generative AI application and sometimes your request may fail or may experience latency.
So, in that case you can go for provision throughput so that you can get some dedicated capacity.
And here you can just purchase provision throughput. Okay, then we have custom model on
demand so I'll get to this in a little bit but before that we have to understand what are custom
models. Okay, next we have tune and first we have custom models. So, it says customize models
using available customization process. So, now let's try and understand the use case scenario
for this through an example. So, let's go to our example on physician notes where we have built
a generative AI application that summarizes physician notes. Now, let's say we are using a
base model from anthropic and since it's been trained on generic internet data it might not
understand the medical terminology. So, in those scenarios you might have to customize your model
for better accuracy. And there are multiple ways and you can customize your model so there can
be distillation, supervised fine tuning, reinforcement fine tuning and continued pre-training.
So, we're going to get into details of all of these but for now just remember there are multiple
ways in which you can customize your base model and once you do that so it should be available here.
And you can see here this is one of the models I tried to create in 2023 but for some reason I'm
not able to delete this. Next we have the prompt router models. So, prompt routers route request
between foundation models from the same family optimizing for response quality and cost.
Now, let's say you build a chatbot using one of the foundation models and the kind of request
you get from the users fall into two categories maybe something very simple maybe summarization
and some tasks could be more complex which involved reasoning. Now, what you can do to optimize
your cost and quality is use prompt routers. So, what prompt router would do is it will
would automatically route request to different models within the same model provider in such a way
that it optimizes for quality and cost. And we're going to see a demo of this later.
Next we have the imported models. So, let's say you have built a model in Amazon SageMaker
or any infrastructure outside AWS then what you can do is you can import that model using S3
into Amazon bedrock and once you import you should be able to see all those models here.
So, what basically AWS is trying to do is so from the governor's perspective you could have all
your models within Amazon bedrock and visible through a single catalog. So, then we have the
marketplace model deployment a list of deployed endpoints. So, if you remember when we are looking
at the model catalog we could see two kind of model serverless and bedrock marketplace.
So, all the models that you have provision using this bedrock marketplace will be visible here.
Okay, that's pretty much it from this lecture. I'll see in the next lecture. Thank you.